A Guide to the Delver Woman's Club Collection, 1960-2019
Archives and Special Collections Department, L. Douglas Wilder Library, Virginia Union University
Archives and Special Collections Department, L. Douglas Wilder Library, Virginia Union University
Delver Woman's Club Collection, 1960-2019
Archives and Special Collections Department, L. Douglas Wilder Library, Virginia Union University
MS-0027
3.5 linear feet (5 boxes, 1 oversized item)
Delver Woman's Club
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Delver Woman's Club; material was added by Vera Ryan in 2004, 2014 and 2019; material was added by Goldie W. Settles in 2006.
Accruals
Further accruals are expected.
Rights Statement for Archival Description
The guide to the Delver Woman's Club at Virginia Union University Archives & Special Collections is licensed under a [CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0) license](https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/)
Admnistrative History
The organization started as the Delver Literary Club in 1917 and disbanded in the early 1940's. Delver Woman's Club was founded in 1945 by the late Mrs. Blanche Coles Case. The organization consists of Christian women who are registered voters and dedicated to providing civic and social interventions in the Richmond community. It has seven interest groups which include Art, Drama, Economic, International Relations, Music, Youth Conservation, and Social and Civic Affairs. The Delver Woman's Club was incorporated in 1949. A Junior Delver Woman's Club was organized in 1951.
Scope and Content
The Delver Woman's Club Collection documents the activities of the organization which consists of consists of Christian women who are registered voters and dedicated to providing civic and social interventions in the Richmond community. It has seven interest groups which include Art, Drama, Economic, International Relations, Music, Youth Conservation, and Social and Civic Affairs. Materials in this collection comprise meeting agendas, Anniversary year books, Annual Luncheon and Dinner meeting, Annual prayer breakfast, Biographies and obituaries, Committees, Constitution and bylaws, Correspondence, Directories. Financial records, Foundation, History, Interest group programs, Meeting and program schedules, Membership rolls, Minutes, Miss Future Delver, News clippings, Newsletters, Photographs, Vesper Service, Awards, certificates, plaques, programs, Trophy plate, NAACP Corp member, Four small containers of slides, 50th anniversary scrapbook, Art Interest Group minutes, Art Interest Group minutes and Art Interest Group – miscellaneous.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically and chronologically.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Delver Woman's Club (Richmond, VA)
Subjects:
African American Women – Virginia – Richmond – Societies and Clubs; African-American Women – Societies and Clubs; Women – Virginia – Richmond – Societies and Clubs; Women – Societies and Clubs – Virginia – Richmond
Contents List
- Agendas (Box-folder 1-1)
- Anniversary year books, 1960-1970 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Anniversary year books, 1995-2005 (Box-folder 1-3)
- Annual Luncheon and Dinner meeting, 1955-2015 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Annual prayer breakfast, 1987-2016 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Biographies and obituaries (Box-folder 1-6)
- Committees (Box-folder 1-7)
- Constitution and bylaws (Box-folder 1-8)
- Correspondence (Box-folder 1-9)
- Directories, 1973-1988 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Directories, 1973-1978 (bound) (Box-folder 1-11)
- Directories, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Financial records, 1961-1977 (Box-folder 1-13)
- Financial records, 1974-2017 (Box-folder 1-14)
- Foundation (Box-folder 1-15)
- History (Box-folder 1-16)
- Interest group programs, 1976-2017 (Box-folder 1-17)
- Meeting and program schedules, 1979-2017 (Box-folder 1-18)
- Membership rolls (Box-folder 1-19)
- Minutes (Box-folder 1-20)
- Miss Future Delver, 1977-1999 (Box-folder 1-21)
- Miss Future Delver, 2002-2005 (Box-folder 1-22)
- News clippings (Box-folder 1-23)
- Newsletters, 1962-2004 (Box-folder 1-24)
- Newsletters, 2005-2016 (Box-folder 1-25)
- Photographs (Box-folder 1-26)
- Vesper Service, 1989-2017 (Box-folder 1-27)
- Framed certificate of appreciation, DuPont, Feb.16, 2001 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Plaque – Living the Dream, Rev. Ricardo Brown, Jan 2013 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Trophy plate in recognition of outstanding contribution to the community, May 1984 to Virgie M. Binford (Box-folder 2-3)
- NAACP Corporate membership award (Box-folder 3-1)
- Four small containers - slides, Aug. 1995 (Box-folder 3-2)
- 50th anniversary scrapbook (Box 4)
- Box 5
  (Accession 2019.023)
  - Art Interest Group minutes, 1969-1988 (Box-folder 5-1)
  - Art Interest Group minutes, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 5-2)
  - Art Interest Group – miscellaneous, 1973-2014 (Box-folder 5-3)
  - Oversized – Presentation check to Virginia Union University, May 18, 2013 (Box-folder 5)